Guide to the Humanities Council Records RG.9.5.1
New York University Archives
- Series I: Administrative Files, early 1970s through 1996; 9.08 Megabytes in 415 computer files; 11 Linear Feet in 19 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize flat box, and 2 folders in additional oversize flat boxes; 4 audiocassettes
  - Subseries I.F: Medical and Dental Humanities, 1977-1991; 2 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 2 folders in oversize flat boxes; 28.9 kilobytes in 4 computer files
    - Program Report, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Expenses, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Dental School 125th Anniversary Celebration--Poster, March 28, 1991 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - Subseries I.G: Publicity and Communications, 1979-1992; 1.5 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes; 196 kilobytes in 51 computer files
    Subseries I.G Publicity and Communications (dated 1979-1992) is comprised of files documenting the the Humanities Council's efforts to promote itself and its programs, including newspaper advertisements, distribution lists, press releases, and a feature in the journal Annals of Scholarship. The Council's communication strategy both within and outside of the NYU community are evidenced with correspondence with faculty, interoffice memos, as well as posters and brochures it printed and distributed.
    - Newspaper Advertisements, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence--NYU Facutly, 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence--Outside NYU, 1979-1985 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Humanities Council Feature in "Annals of Scholarship", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - External and Internal Publicity Efforts, 1983-1984 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Brochures, 1983-1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_5
    - General Mailing Lists, 1983-1992
      - Paper Records, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Electronic Records, 1988-1989; RG_9-5-1_ER_24
    - Interoffice Communication, 1983-1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_27
- Series II: NYU Programming, 1976-1995; 13.75 Linear Feet in 28 manuscript boxes, 3 half-manuscript boxes, and 17 folders in oversize flat boxes; 4.9 Megabytes in 221 computer files; 2 VHS; 17 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 95 audiocassettes
  Historical Note
  The Humanities Council's primary function was planning, supporting, and promoting interdisciplinary humanities instruction and events for the New York University community. In its early years, the Council focused on creating seminar-style classes, organizing colloquia for NYU faculty members, and planning lectures. Colloquia topics were often repeated several years in a row. The Council worked with visiting scholars from the late 1970s through the mid-1980s to develop programming, primarily planning lectures for the Distinguished Lecture Series. Other lectures and lecture series were planned to tie into events, such as the Bicentennial of the American Constitution, the 25th anniversary of Vatican II, and the 10th anniversary of the Humanities Council. In 1984, NYU Emeritus Professor Sidney Hook was chosen to deliver the National Endowment for the Humanities's 13th Annual Jefferson Lecture, which he gave at NYU and the Council had a large hand in planning the event.
  During the late 1980s, the Council moved away from supporting seminars and long-running lecture series and programmed events of different formats on a more case-by-case basis. The Council engaged in planning symposia, conferences, readings, tributes, and exhibitions over the 20 years it operated, but these events were more prevalent in the Council's later years. Many of these events were planned in cooperation with other offices of the University, including the Institute for African American Affairs, the Libraries, and Ireland House.
  The Council also planned programming for students at NYU's medical and dental schools, and these events followed a similar pattern: more structured, recurring programs, such as the Medical School Honors Lecture Series, dominated during the Council's first decade of operation, with fewer and less structured programs in the Council's second decade.
  Series II: New York University Programming (dated 1976-1995) includes materials documenting events and programs that the Humanities Council developed for the NYU community. This series contains paper and electronic records, the majority of which are paper. Records were primarily created during the event planning process, and files in all subseries include similar materials. Most of the records in this series include correspondence between the Humanities Council and participants, and many include information about event planning, including booking space, printing promotional materials, and mailing lists for potential invitees. Files also include copies of invitations and event programs, and some contain event scripts or transcripts. Files related to seminars, colloquia, and symposia also contain program proposals and planning guidelines. This series also includes promotional materials, including brochures for seminar and lecture offerings and posters for various events. Many lectures and some parts of other events were recorded, and these recordings are incorporated into the event files. Event recordings are all audio with one exception: the "God's Trombones" tribute was recorded on video. The subjects addressed in thse programs offer insight into academic trends and concerns of humanities scholars during this period.
  Subseries II.A Seminars, 1976-1995
  Subseries II.B Colloquia, 1977-1995
  Subseries II.C Visiting Scholars Programming, 1977-1992
  Subseries II.D Lectures, 1977-1994
  Subseries II.E Medical and Dental Schools Programming, 1978-1992
  Subseries II.F Conferences and Symposia, 1978-1995
  Subseries II.G Other Programming, 1978-1994
  - Subseries II.A: Seminars, 1976-1995; 5.75 Linear Feet in 11 manuscript boxes, 1 half-manuscript box, and 3 folders in oversize flat boxes; 2 audiocassettes; 50.4 kilobytes in 18 computer files
    Subseries II.A Seminars (dated 1976-1995) includes materials related to different seminars the Humanities Council planned, sponsored, or funded during its existence. Undergraduate and graduate seminars are represented with planning files, which include correspondence, calls for proposals, proposals, and Council responses. Additionally, some files are associated with specific seminars, seminar guidelines, applications, evaluations, course listings, posters, and flyers. This subseries also includes files with similar materials regarding the Sesquicentennial Seminar Series, seminars for faculty, seminars for visiting scholars, ad-hoc seminars, and other classes and workshops supported by the Council.
    - Undergraduate Seminars, 1976-1985
      - Undergraduate Seminar Planning Files, 1977-1990
        - Paper Records, 1977-1990
          - 1977-1978 (Box 36, Folder 1-10)
          - 1978-1979 (Box 37, Folder 1-12)
          - 1978-1980 (Box 38, Folder 1-15)
          - 1980 (Box 39, Folder 1-7)
          - 1981-1983 (Box 40, Folder 2-6, 10, 12-13)
          - 1985 (Box 45, Folder 3-4)
          - 1987-1990 (Box 46, Folder 2-3)
        - Electronic Records, 1983-1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_71
      - Peripatetic Stories: Poetry of Persia, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Drama in Performance in New York, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 9, Box 47, Folder 1)
      - The Physician in Literature, 1980 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Undergraduate Seminar Applications and Guidelines, 1981, 1984-1985
        - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_52
        - Paper Records, 1981, 1984-1985 (Box 40, Folder 1, Box 45)
      - Classics Seminar, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - The American West in Film, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Call for Proposals, 1983-1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_39
      - Italian and Italian-American Languages, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Seminar Posters, 1977-1980 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 13, Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Seminar Assessments, 1977-1980 (Box 41, Folder 1-5)
    - Undergraduate and Graduate Seminars Course Listings, 1977, 1985 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Sesquicentennial Humanities Seminars, Spring 1981 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Faculty Seminars, 1981-1983
      - Seminar on Regulation, December 17, 1981 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0219)
      - Seminar on Science, Technology, and Society, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Graduate School of Business Administration Humanities Seminars, 1982-1983
      - Paper Records, 1982-1983 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - Poster, 1982-1983 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - George Watson--Ideology and Critical Theory Seminar, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_73
    - Humanities Seminars for Visiting Scholars, 1984-1989
      - Paper Records, 1984-1989 (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1984-1989 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 13)
      - Electronic Records, 1984-1989; RG_9-5-1_ER_56
    - Graduate Seminar Planning Files, 1984-1989
      - Paper Records, 1984-1989 (Box 45, Folder 6)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_50
    - Graduate Seminar Call for Proposals, 1985; RG_9-5-1_ER_38
    - Seminar Fliers, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Supper Seminars, Spring 1989 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Seminar on Poeta en Nueva York by Federico García Lorca, 1990-1991
      - Paper Records, 1990-1991 (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - Electronic Records, 1990-1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_62
    - Professor Hertzberg's Talmud Class for Trustees, Administrators, and Faculty, 1991-1993 (Box 42, Folder 5-6)
    - Regulation and Deregulation Seminar Series, 1993
      - Paper Records, 1993 (Box 46, Folder 4-5)
      - Audio Recording, November 12, 1983 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0224)
    - Modern Japanese History Workshop, 1994-1995 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Workshop on Approaches to Russian and Soviet History, 1995 (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II.B: Colloquia, 1977-1995; 4 Linear Feet in 8 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in an oversize box; 9 audiocassettes; 980.2 kilobytes in 53 computer files
    Subseries II.B Colloquia (Dated 1977-1995) includes administrative files regarding colloquia planning and programming and files related to specific colloquia. These administrative files include proposals, reports, calls for participation, lists, calendars, guidelines, and expense files. One 1995 file about the status of faculty colloquia includes correspondence from faculty that demonstrates their feelings about the importance and efficacy of the faculty colloquia program at that time. Files for individual colloquia include correspondence with facilitators and participants, session plans, and occasionally materials, like audio recordings, tied to a specific lecture or meeting. Colloquia topics and the number of years they were repeated offer insight into academic trends and concerns of the period.
    - Colloquia Proposals, 1977-1986 (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    - Colloquium on Contemporary Critical Methods, 1977-1980 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Colloquium on Teaching of Ethics and Moral Values, 1977-1984
      - Paper Records, 1977-1983
        - 1977-1978 (Box 22, Folder 9-19)
        - 1978 (Box 21, Folder 9)
        - 1978-1979 (Box 23, Folder 1-12)
        - 1979-1983 (Box 24, Folder 1-13)
        - Undated (Box 25, Folder 1-5)
      - Robert Coles--"Children and Ethical Conflict" Lecture, February 11, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Charles W. Powers Lecture, December 3, 1981
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0196)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0197)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_43
    - Colloquium on Theory and Practice of Avant-Garde, 1977-1991
      - Lecture by Ellen Stewart, April 10, 1991 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0125)
      - Paper Records, 1977-1991 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Colloquium on the Interdisciplinary Study of the Mind, 1978-1980 (Box 25, Folder 7-8)
    - Colloquium on Poetry and Poetics, 1978-1983 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Colloquia Reports, 1979-1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Colloquium on Ritual Performance and Performance Ritual, 1979-1984 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Colloquium on Italian and Italian-American Languages, 1979-1986 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Lists of Colloquia, 1979-1993
      - Paper Records, 1979-1993 (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
      - Electronic Records, 1983-1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_61
    - Archway Colloquium: Funding the Arts, October 20, 1980 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0202)
    - Colloquium on Psychoaesthetics, 1981-1982 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Call for participants, 1981-1982, 1990-1993
      - Paper Records, 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Electronic Records, 1990-1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_37
    - Colloquium on Comparative Social History, 1981-1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Colloquium on The Enlightenment, 1981-1986 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Colloquium on Sex and Gender Studies, 1981-1986
      - Paper Records, 1981-1986 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Audio Recording, September 28, 1983 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0168)
      - Electronic Records, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_46
    - Colloquium on Telecommunications, 1982-1983
      - Paper Records, 1982-1983 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Audio Recording, November 18, 1983 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0178)
    - Mailing Lists, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Colloquium on Law and Literature, 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Colloquium on Cultural Pluralism, 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Colloquium on the History of Science and Medicine, 1982-1986 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Colloquium on Critical Theory and Writing, 1983-1984 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Colloquia Calendars, 1983-1994; RG_9-5-1_ER_40
    - Colloquium on Ancient Civilizations, 1983-1986 (Box 26, Folder 10-11)
    - Colloquium on The Catholic Bishops and the Shaping of Nuclear and Other Public Policies, 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 12, Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recording, September 24, 1984
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0203)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0204)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_47
    - Applications and Guidelines for Running A Humanities Council Faculty Colloquium, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Colloquium on Cultural Implications of Computers, Robots, and Artificial Intellegence, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Colloquium on War and Peace Studies, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Colloquium on Literature and Visual Arts, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Colloquium on Post-Industrial Culture and the Emergence of New Values, 1985-1987
      - Paper Records, 1985-1987 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Poster, 1985-1987 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Colloquium on European Society and Politics, 1985-1986, 1991-1992
      - Paper Records, 1985-1986 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Electronic Records, 1991-1992; RG_9-5-1_ER_44
    - Colloquium on Law and Society, 1986, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Graduate Student Colloquia, 1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_51
    - Colloquia Expenses, 1991; RG_9-5-1_ER_41
    - Colloquium on Power and the Delegation of Power, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Colloquium on Psychoanalysis and the Humanities, 1993; RG_9-5-1_ER_45
    - Colloquia Newsletter, 1993-1994; RG_9-5-1_ER_42
    - Colloquium on the Renaissance, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Status of Faculty Colloquia, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Environmental Colloquium, undated (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0198)
  - Subseries II.C: Visiting Scholars Programming, 1977-1992; 6.5 Linear Feet in 12 manuscript boxes and 8 folders in oversize flat boxes; 9 Quarter_Inch_Audio_Reel; 44 audiocassettes; 188.4 kilobytes in 80 computer files
    Subseries II.C Visiting Scholars Programming (dated 1977-1992) includes files documenting prominent academics' visits to NYU and any functions, events, or programs they planned with the Humanities Council. Files for each visitor include varying combinations of records, including correspondence between the Council and the visitor, logistical planning information, invitations, mailing lists, the text of lectures, and event scripts. This subseries also contains posters advertising visiting scholar events and audio recordings of some events.
    - René Wellek Lecture, June 27, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Sir Paul Wright--"The British Monarchy in 1997", November 16, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Vassili Vassilikos--"The Greek Writer Today", 1978 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Bernard V. Bothmer--"Art in the Age of Tutankhamen", 1978 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Lionel Casson--"Pompeii: A.D. 79 to 1979 A.D.", April 4, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Jeremy Bernstein--"Einstein and the Philosophy of Science", April 30, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - E. Haverkamp-Begemann--"Rembrandt and the Old Testament", May 1, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Jaques Derrida--"La Loi du Genre", November 7, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Carlos Fuentes--"Into the 80s...Reflections of a Writer", 1979
      - Paper Records, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Poster, 1979 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Audio Recording, December 13, 1979 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0060)
    - Christopher Lasch--"The Nuclear Family and its Critics", February 28, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Yeshi Dönden--"Compassion in the Tibetan Medical Tradition", March 12, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - R.D. Keynes--"Darwin and the Beagle", March 24, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Stephen J. Gould--"The Fossil Record: Major Patterns in the History of Life", 1980
      - Paper Records, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - Poster, 1980 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 17)
    - George Steiner--"Can One Say Anything About the Meaning of a Literary Text?", 1980
      - Paper Records, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - Afternoon Seminar, October 8, 1980
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0061)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0063)
      - Evening Lecture, October 8, 1980 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0062)
    - Seminar Proposal: The Polish Crisis and its Implications for Modern Europe, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - Ronald Dworkin--"Human Rights and Economic Wrongs", April 16, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Abba Eban--"Recent Changes in International Relations", April 28, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Renato Nicolini--"Cities and Street Fairs", May 2, 1981
      - Paper Records, May 2, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 20, Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Poster, May 2, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Bernard Crick--"1984: Satire or Prophecy", October 1, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Leon Edel--"T.S. Eliot: The Journey to Lausanne, 1981
      - Paper Records, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Poster, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recordings, October 29, 1981
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0036)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0050)
    - Lord Hugh Caradon--"United Nations Opportunities in the Middle East and Cyprus", 1982
      - Paper Records, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Posters, 1982 (Box Shared University Archives 097, Folder 17, Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Audio Recording, April 12, 1982 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0040)
    - Asa Briggs, Lord Briggs of Lewes--"The University Scene in Europe: Traditions and Experiments", 1982
      - Paper Records, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recording, April 14, 1982
        - Audio -- 1 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0035)
        - Audio -- 2 of 2 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0038)
    - Seminar on The Nuclear Threat to Humankind, 1982 (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Zvi Yavetz--"Charismatic Leadership in the Ancient World", April 27, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Reinhard Bendix--"Objective and Subjective Meaning in History", April 29, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - William Arrowsmith--"T.S. Eliot's Lune de Miel", 1982
      - Paper Records, 1982 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - Audio Recording, May 6, 1982 (Box 90, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0051)
    - William Arrowsmith--"The Discoloring of 'Seems': Antonioni's Blow-Up", March 23, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - John Koumoulides Lecture on Cyprus, 1983-1984
      - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_57
    - John Rawls--"Conception of the Person, Political Not Metaphysical", 1983
      - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - Electronic Records, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_58
      - Poster, 1983 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recording, November 1, 1983 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0072)
    - Thomas A. Sebok--"The Semiotics of Magic/The Magic of Semiotics", November 2, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Henry Steele Commager--"Restoration of the Community of Learning", 1983
      - Paper Records, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - Electronic Records, 1983; RG_9-5-1_ER_53
    - Anthony Aveni Lecture, November 18, 1983 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0201)
    - Robert Warner--"The Archives at Fifty...The Past is Prologue", 1983-1984
      - Paper Records, 1983-1984 (Box 31, Folder 12, Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Electronic Records, 1983-1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_67
    - A Reading by Bernard Malamud, 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 35, Folder 17)
      - Posters, 1984 (Box Shared University Archives 155, Folder 5, Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_32
    - Raymond Carr--"The Socialist Experiement in Spain", 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_69
    - Michael Brock--"'What Else Could We Do?' The British Decision for War, August 1914", 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Electronic Records, 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_64
    - John W. Blassingame--"Slavery in Black Literature", 1984; RG_9-5-1_ER_59
    - Sir John Sinclair Morrison--"An Ancient Greek Warship", 1984 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Tom Bishop--"Cocteau and a Generation of Avant-Garde Theater", 1984 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Father Walter J. Ong--"Writing is a Technology That Restructures Consciousness", 1984 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Sir Steven Runciman--"The Crusades and the Christians of the East", 1984 (Box 32, Folder 5-6)
    - Sir Ronald Syme--"Julius Caesar: Drama, Legend, History", 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
      - Audio Recording, November 14, 1984 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0289)
    - Umberto Eco--"On Writing an Historical Novel", 1984
      - Paper Records, 1984 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Audio Recording, December 6, 1984 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0188)
    - A Selection from the Humanities Council Distinguished Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Dick Wilson--"The New Future of Hong Kong", 1985
      - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
      - Audio Recording, March 18, 1985 (Box 95, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0195)
    - Yigael Yadin Dead Sea Scrolls Lecture--Cancelled, March 18, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Sir David Hunt--"Three Greek Islands", March 1985 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Lord Anthony Quinton--"Religion and Science in Three Major Religions", 1985
      - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Audio Recording, April 17, 1985 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0205)
    - Seminar on Federal Policy and Funding of the Arts with Francis Hodsoll, 1985
      - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - "Subsidized Muse: Public Funding of the Arts in the United States" Lecture, October 1, 1985 (Box 96, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0209)
    - Benjamin Hrushovski--"The Modern Jewish Revolution: Transformations in Culture and Consciousness (1881-1985)"
      - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 10-11)
      - Audio Recording, October 10, 1985 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0129)
    - Francis Mason--"Balanchine: Belief So Fantastic", 1985
      - Paper Records, 1985 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
      - Audio Recording, December 4, 1985 (Box 92, Audiocassette 9-5-1.0139)
    - David Miller--"The Future of Socialism in the Advanced Societies", 1986
      - Paper Records, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Audio Recordings, February 18, 1986
        - Audio Reel -- 1 of 2 (Box 76, Quarter inch audio reel 9-5-1.0004)